<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: productivity | pietrushnic's world]]></title>
  <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/categories/productivity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-04T10:17:13+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[pietrushnic]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pierushnic@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improve productivity with Goolge history using bookmarks and Chrome extensions]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/07/30/how-to-use-google-search-activity-to-improve-productivity/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-30T02:40:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/07/30/how-to-use-google-search-activity-to-improve-productivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>The idea of this post is very simple (as usually)  and I wonder why I didn&rsquo;t thought
about it earlier. The point is to use history of your Google queries to improve
productivity. Most of things that we google can be replaced for example by browser
extensions, bookmarks or rss feeds. Thats how we can gain few additional free seconds on
each google-type-click cycle.</p>

<h2>Statistics</h2>

<p>Depending on different factors we spend a lot of time in browser. I cannot find
statistics for desktops but for mobile <a href="http://blog.flurry.com/bid/95723/Flurry-Five-Year-Report-It-s-an-App-World-The-Just-Web-Lives-in-It">Flurry</a>
researches are probably relevant enough. Simplifying this statistics and assuming that desktop market
is similar (it is probably to big simplification for some of you but IMHO it is
good for reflections on this blog):</p>

<ul>
<li>access Facebook, social networks (+18%, +6%)</li>
<li>play some games (<a href="http://allthingsd.com/20130325/a-look-ahead-at-gdc-its-mobile-vs-consoles-in-fight-for-game-developers-attention/">lets say 30%</a> of our 32% from Flurry report +13%)</li>
<li>web browsing time (+20%)</li>
<li>entertain</li>
<li>read news</li>
<li>use productivity tools</li>
</ul>


<p>We have at least 60 percent of our time in web browser. That&rsquo;s explain Google&rsquo;s
ideas about ChromOS and competition on browser market. Of course if take look a
this in short therm it look ridiculous but in long term it may be true. Even if this estimation
not match your behavior than ask yourself what percentage of time spent in
browser proves that improving productivity using google queries data does not
make sense ? Especially when doing this will not consume lot of your time.</p>

<h2>Productivity improvements based on my google history</h2>

<p>Below I will show how I improve my productivity using top queries and top sites
from <a href="https://history.google.com/history/">google history</a>. These are my results
that I found after choosing <code>Show more trends</code>:</p>

<h3>Top queries</h3>

<ol>
<li><code>ztm gdańsk</code>          &ndash; public transportation in my home town</li>
<li><code>usdpln</code>              &ndash; Polish Zloty to US Dollar rate</li>
<li><code>rozkład jazdy pkp</code>   &ndash; Polish state railways schedule</li>
<li><code>intc</code>                &ndash; Intel Corporation stocks rate</li>
<li><code>radio polska stacja</code> &ndash; Polish Internet radio station</li>
</ol>


<p>First of all I was surprised that I googled these things so many times. Especially
for point 5 :). To improve my daily routine with these data I use following
applications:</p>

<h4>Public transporation</h4>

<p>I used well known Polish application for public transpiration in biggest cities
&ndash; <a href="http://jakdojade.pl/">jakdojade.pl</a>. If you register on their page they give
you possibility to save travel directions, so I used it to save my common
destinations. Of course I put it on my bookmark bar as it is one of the most
used links.</p>

<h4>Currency ratio</h4>

<p>After thinking a while I realize that few requirements have to be met for me.
I need below fields:</p>

<ul>
<li>USD/PLN rate</li>
<li>EUR/PLN rate</li>
<li>gold ounce in US Dollars or XAUUSD</li>
<li>silver ounce in US Dollars or XAGUSD</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately I was unhappy with choice presented on Chrome extension site
because I find that it is not easy to met my expectations &ndash; this is probably
market niche to explore. For today I choose <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/currency-converter/lncdobdbibdgoiohgnflmjajfphcnakg">Currency Converter</a>.
It has pretty good rate 4.5 star/444 opinions. One thing I don&rsquo;t like is that I
cannot set every field as I wish. Ratio always relate to recent changed position.
I also cannot display stock rate. That&rsquo;s why I will have to use one another
extension.</p>

<h4>Railways schedule</h4>

<p>Right now there is nothing I can do for this one than adding to bookmark bar as
a recently visited site.</p>

<h4>Stocks ticker</h4>

<p>There are plenty of extensions for Chrome and not a lot of really good one. I
found <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/stock-tracker/gphdmnilpmjaioploikmbpgkjfbagidf">Stock Tracker</a>
useful because it shows price in the icon on toolbar. But it is not free from
small bugs, for example INTC price is 4 digit with dot (00.00) and inadequate
font size selection causing that last digit is visible only in half, which cause
it hard to read. Good thing is that after pushing extension button on toolbar I
get stock chart and can see the trend.</p>

<h3>Top sites</h3>

<ol>
<li><code>stackoverflow.com</code></li>
<li><code>en.wikipedia.org</code></li>
<li><code>github.com</code></li>
<li><code>www.chessgames.com</code></li>
<li><code>pl.wikipedia.org</code></li>
</ol>


<p>Probably most of this pages are well known for you. What we can do with this
information ?</p>

<p>For
<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/lookup-companion-for-wiki/dhgpkiiipkgmckicafkhcihkcldbdeej">wiki</a> and <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/search-stackoverflow/gmdolelhfhbldobljhbhdgljbajhfilj">stackoverflow</a> there are extensions that help get search engine of
those sites. I found that usually google +stockoverflow works better than this
extension but it is worth a try. Wiki works without any problem and only our
habits can stop us by using it.</p>

<p>I use a lot of <a href="http://www.chess.com">chess.com</a> what I found useful with this
is <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/chesscom-notifier/khihkgdcfbjdnfgalkjnimbmofnhhpho">Chess.com Notifier</a>
it change color when some pending move in my games. Unfortunately I get to
<a href="http://www.chessgames.com">www.chessgames.com</a> though google looking for
particular position in game &ndash; right now I can&rsquo;t find easy way to improve this
other than paying for access to good database with defined interface or using my
own database.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure that you have some clues how to improve your productivity using Google
history or you will find application for suggested plugins. Anyway, I whish you
good luck.</p>

<h2>At the end &ndash; the hard thing</h2>

<p>Switching our behaviors to something different is really hard thing. If we
always go to google and type well know query and trying to switch to something
new like replacing this behavior with clicking link or running extension could
be hard. This new action at the begging can be even slower than old. That&rsquo;s why
people resign after few tries. Most people also don&rsquo;t like changes as adage said
&ldquo;better the devil you know&rdquo;. However only those who try to change something in
their lives can reach success. And as story of Thomas Edison proves you have to
try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workflow imporovement with Open Source tools - part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/workflow-imporovement-with-open-source-tools/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-16T22:16:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/workflow-imporovement-with-open-source-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p>I want to start a series of articles to describe how I improve my workflow with
geeky Open Source applications. I will concentrate on terminal applications that
I try to use in my GTD process.</p>

<h3>Terminal</h3>

<h4>Solarized gnome-terminal</h4>

<p>If you already don&rsquo;t know what solarized color scheme is then please take a look
at <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">this page</a>. To install solarized
colorscheme in gnome-terminal simply follow instruction from this <a href="https://github.com/sigurdga/gnome-terminal-colors-solarized">git repository</a>.</p>

<h3>Mutt again</h3>

<p>During last days I spent a lot of time to tweak my mutt configuration. Here I
will give you few hints about things that I learned.</p>

<h4>Solarized mutt</h4>

<p>To enable solarized colorscheme in mutt simply download one of scheme files from <a href="https://github.com/altercation/mutt-colors-solarized">github</a>. If you installed
dark scheme for your gnome-terminal then I suggest <code>mutt-colors-solarized-dark-16.muttrc</code>.
Copy this file for example to <code>$HOME/.mutt</code> and source it in muttrc file:
<code>
source $HOME/.mutt/mutt-colors-solarized-dark-16.muttrc
</code></p>

<h4>Width of From column</h4>

<p>Usually from field in today&rsquo;s emails is longer than 19 characters. If this
happens mutt by default will not display whole string. To change this behavior
you can manipulate <code>index_format</code> variable. I set mine to 30:

<code>
set index_format="%4C %Z %{%b %d} %-30.30L (%4l) %s"
</code>
</p>

<h4>Sidebar</h4>

<p>Finally I gave up sidebar for using latest code without annoying <code>tls_socket_read</code> error.
Switching between IMAP folders is not so bad, you can quickly display all
folders by <code>c&lt;Tab&gt;&lt;Tab&gt;</code> or simply <code>y</code></p>

<h4>Offlineimap</h4>

<p>This is probably best program to synchronize your emails with local storage. It
also has feature that allow synchronization between different IMAP servers but
I&rsquo;m not using it. Few things are crucial when using <code>offlineimap</code>:</p>

<ul>
<li>probably easiest way to keep passwords secret is using python hooks for gnome-keyring,
detailed description how to integrate it with <code>offlineimap</code> is
<a href="http://www.clasohm.com/blog/one-entry?entry_id=90957">here</a>. Debian name of
<code>gnome-python2-gnomekeyring</code> is different: <code>python-gnomekeyring</code>.</li>
<li>Use meaningful <code>localfolders</code> because you will use it in <code>mutt</code> configuration</li>
</ul>


<p>Typical configuration of <code>$HOME/.offlineimaprc</code>:
```
[mbnames]
enabled = yes
filename = ~/.mutt/muttrc.mailboxes
header = &ldquo;mailboxes &rdquo;
peritem = &ldquo;+%(accountname)s/%(foldername)s&rdquo;
sep = &ldquo; &rdquo;
footer = &ldquo;\n&rdquo;</p>

<p>[general]
metadata = ~/.offlineimap
maxsyncaccounts = 5
maxconnections = 2
accounts = account1, account2
status_backend = sqlite
pythonfile = ~/.mutt/offlineimap.py</p>

<p>[Account account1]
autorefresh = 3
localrepository = acc1_local
remoterepository = acc1_remote</p>

<p>[Repository acc1_local]
type = Maildir
localfolders = ~/.mail/account1</p>

<p>[Repository acc2_remote]
type = Gmail
remoteusereval = get_username(&ldquo;account1&rdquo;)
remotepasseval = get_password(&ldquo;account1&rdquo;)
sslcacertfile = /etc/ssl/certs/ca-certificates.crt</p>

<p>[Account account2]
autorefresh = 3
localrepository = acc2_local
remoterepository = acc2_remote</p>

<p>[Repository acc2_local]
type = Maildir
localfolders = ~/.mail/account2</p>

<p>[Repository acc2_remote]
type = Gmail
remoteusereval = get_username(&ldquo;account2&rdquo;)
remotepasseval = get_password(&ldquo;account2&rdquo;)
sslcacertfile = /etc/ssl/certs/ca-certificates.crt
```</p>

<p>What this means by section:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>[mbnames]</code> &ndash; automatically create mailboxes folders according to your
configuration on IMAP server</li>
<li><code>[general]</code> &ndash; most important things here are self explanatory accounts
variable and <code>max{syncaccounts,connections}</code>, first said how many accounts
should be synchronized and second how many simultaneous connections should be
used</li>
<li><code>[Account *]</code> &ndash; contain sync refresh time in minutes (<code>autorefresh</code>) and link
to local and remote repository definitions (<code>localrepository</code> and
<code>remoterepository</code>)</li>
<li><code>[Repository *]</code> &ndash; for local folder and its type and for remote gnome-keyring
configuration</li>
</ul>


<h4>Multiple account configuration</h4>

<p>To simplify multiple accounts configuration I added two things:</p>

<ul>
<li>separated account files configuration &ndash; in my case placed in <code>$HOME/.mutt/accounts</code>
<code>
set postponed   = +account1@server.com/Drafts
set spoolfile   = +account1@server.com/INBOX
set record      = +account1@server.com/Sent
set from        = 'account1@server.com'
set realname    = 'My Name'
set smtp_url    = smtps://acc1@smtp.server.com:587
set smtp_pass   = $my_pass
set signature   = "~/.mutt/signature.example"
</code></li>
<li>folder hooks for particular account &ndash; it cause automatic loading of
configurations when folder was changed (in <code>$HOME/muttrc</code>):
<code>
folder-hook 'account1@server.com' 'source $HOME/.mutt/accounts/account1'
</code></li>
</ul>


<h4>Separate mailing list file</h4>

<p>I keep my mailing list configuration file separated and source it in my
<code>$HOME/.muttrc</code>. I&rsquo;m not mailing list advanced user, so right now I have manually
created IMAP folders and Gmail filters to move mails from mailing list to this
folders. On the mutt side I use <code>subscribe</code> command to indicate that particular
mail id is a mailing list.</p>

<h3>Personal informations</h3>

<p>Some informations in my configuration files shouldn&rsquo;t be available for all. I
mean my email account configuration, my todo list, passwords and things like
that. To store this informations I use additional private git repository and use
it as a submodule for my workspace configuration. I wrote post about keeping
configuration using git
<a href="/blog/2012/02/19/improve-productivity-by-tracking-work">here</a> and
<a href="/blog/2012/02/20/improve-productivity-by-tracking-work_20">here</a>.</p>

<h3>Taskwarrior and vit</h3>

<p>I really like <code>taskwarrior</code> as a GTD tool but I was tired of writing everything
every time I wanted to change sth. I found <code>vit</code>. Vit is a vi-like interface
to task list generated by <code>taskwarrior</code> it works really great. Mostly it is
written in perl and there is no official repository for its code base but latest
version is from April 2013. I use lot of <code>project:</code> and <code>+flag</code> to update my
TODO list. I prefer <code>long</code> filter.</p>

<h4>My taskwarrior projects and flags</h4>

<p>I have few ongoing projects like <code>blog</code>, <code>productivity</code> and <code>ideas</code>. In addition I use
few flags like <code>ideas</code>, <code>finish</code>, <code>enhancement</code>, <code>fix</code> or <code>bug</code>. So when I
connect project and flag I get few categories like:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>blog ideas</code> for new articles ideas</li>
<li><code>blog finish</code> for articles that should be finished ASAP</li>
<li><code>blog bug/fix</code> for articles that have to be changed for some reason</li>
<li><code>productivity bug/fix</code> for productivity tools configuration improvements</li>
<li><code>productivity ideas</code> for new improvements</li>
</ul>


<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I think this is enough for first post from this series. Hope it was helpful. If
yes then please share, if no then comment what I should improve. Thanks for
reading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tmux as screen replacement and productivity accelerator]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/04/06/tmux/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-06T05:29:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/04/06/tmux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I wrote in <a href="/blog/2013/03/19/debian-switching-to-unstable">previous post</a> I
switched from GNU screen to <a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net">tmux</a>. I use it for a
few moths and have to said that I&rsquo;m really impressed by simplicity, performance
and community support in this project. In this post I want to discuss my
configuration and useful additions for it like tmuxinator, session logging,
colors or status bar configuration.</p>

<h3>Basics</h3>

<p>Debian contain <code>tmux</code> package but for stable and testing release it is pretty
old version. Personally I use <code>unstable</code> version where <code>tmux</code> was delivered in
<code>1.7~svn2819-1</code> version.
<code>
sudo apt-get install tmux
</code>
To start session simply type <code>tmux</code>. Tmux uses <code>C-b</code>/ <code>Ctrl-b</code> as a prefix for
commands. If you switch from GNU screen then at the beginning you can experience
some annoying situations but after few days everything should back to normal.</p>

<p>Most used keybiddings:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>C-b c</code> &ndash; create new window</li>
<li><code>C-b ,</code> &ndash; rename current window</li>
<li><code>C-b n</code> &ndash; next window</li>
<li><code>C-b p</code> &ndash; previous window</li>
<li><code>C-b l</code> &ndash; last window</li>
<li><code>C-b d</code> &ndash; disconnect</li>
<li><code>C-b k</code> &ndash; kill current window</li>
<li><code>C-b K</code> &ndash; kill tmux server</li>
<li><code>C-b [</code> &ndash; enter copy mode</li>
<li><code>C-b ]</code> &ndash; paste last copied buffer</li>
<li><code>C-b :</code> &ndash; tmux command line</li>
<li><code>C-b w</code> &ndash; windows list</li>
<li><code>C-b ?</code> &ndash; help</li>
</ul>


<p>Full list can be found <a href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi?query=tmux&amp;sektion=1#KEY+BINDINGS">here</a>.</p>

<h3>Configuration</h3>

<p>Tmux keeps its configuration in <code>$HOME/.tmux.conf</code>. My configuration mixes
some tmux examples with code that I found in the net. This file can be found on
my github repository <a href="https://github.com/pietrushnic/workspace/blob/master/dotfiles/tmux.conf">here</a>. First section contain some general configuration:
```</p>

<h1>confirm before killing a window or the server</h1>

<p>bind-key k confirm kill-window
bind-key K confirm kill-server</p>

<h1>toggle statusbar</h1>

<p>bind-key b set-option status</p>

<h1>ctrl+left/right cycles thru windows</h1>

<p>bind-key -n C-right next
bind-key -n C-left prev</p>

<h1>scrollback buffer n lines</h1>

<p>set -g history-limit 10000</p>

<h1>listen for activity on all windows</h1>

<p>set -g bell-action any</p>

<h1>on-screen time for display-panes in ms</h1>

<p>set -g display-panes-time 2000</p>

<h1>start window indexing at one instead of zero</h1>

<p>set -g base-index 1</p>

<h1>enable wm window titles</h1>

<p>set -g set-titles on</p>

<h1>wm window title string (uses statusbar variables)</h1>

<p>set -g set-titles-string &ldquo;tmux.#I.#W&rdquo;</p>

<h1>statusbar</h1>

<p>set -g display-time 2000
<code>
After that I have implemented [solarized](http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized) colors (dark theme):
</code></p>

<h3>COLOUR (Solarized dark)</h3>

<h1>default statusbar colors</h1>

<p>set-option -g status-bg black #base02
set-option -g status-fg yellow #yellow
set-option -g status-attr default</p>

<h1>default window title colors</h1>

<p>set-window-option -g window-status-fg brightblue #base0
set-window-option -g window-status-bg default</p>

<h1>set-window-option -g window-status-attr dim</h1>

<h1>active window title colors</h1>

<p>set-window-option -g window-status-current-fg brightred #orange
set-window-option -g window-status-current-bg default</p>

<h1>set-window-option -g window-status-current-attr bright</h1>

<h1>use vi-like keys</h1>

<p>setw -g mode-keys vi</p>

<h1>pane border</h1>

<p>set-option -g pane-border-fg black #base02
set-option -g pane-active-border-fg brightgreen #base01</p>

<h1>message text</h1>

<p>set-option -g message-bg black #base02
set-option -g message-fg brightred #orange</p>

<h1>pane number display</h1>

<p>set-option -g display-panes-active-colour blue #blue
set-option -g display-panes-colour brightred #orange
```
To make solarized colors work on my setup was quite challenging, because there
are many things to set (vim, terminal, putty etc.). If you need any advice I can
write something about this. Right now it is beyond the scope of this post.</p>

<p>At the end of my tmux configuration I&rsquo;ve some fancy status bar:
```</p>

<h1>clock</h1>

<p>set-window-option -g clock-mode-colour green #green</p>

<h1>center align the window list</h1>

<p>set -g status-justify centre</p>

<h1>show some useful stats but only when tmux is started</h1>

<h1>outside of Xorg, otherwise dwm statusbar shows these already</h1>

<p>set -g status-right &ldquo;&rdquo;
set -g status-left &ldquo;&rdquo;
if &lsquo;[ -z &ldquo;$DISPLAY&rdquo; ]&rsquo; &lsquo;set -g status-left &ldquo;[#[fg=green] #H ][#[default]]&rdquo;&rsquo;
if &lsquo;[ -z &ldquo;$DISPLAY&rdquo; ]&rsquo; &lsquo;set -g status-right &ldquo;[ #[fg=magenta]#(cat /proc/loadavg | cut -d \&rdquo; \&ldquo; -f 1,2,3)#[default] ][ #[fg=cyan,bright]%a %Y-%m-%d %H:%M #[default]]&rdquo;&rsquo;
if &lsquo;[ -z &ldquo;$DISPLAY&rdquo; ]&rsquo; &lsquo;set -g status-right-length 50&rsquo;
```
I think that mostly this is self explanatory. This how it look in work:
<a href="/assets/images/tmux-screen.png"><img class="center" src="/assets/images/tmux-screen.png" width="300" height="400"></a></p>

<h3>tmuxinator</h3>

<p>I spend some time to realize what is the best way of managing windows and panes
in tmux. Especially I was interested in setting some windows at tmux startup.
Finally I found <a href="https://github.com/aziz/tmuxinator">tmuxinator</a> small but useful
project delivered through <code>gem</code> system. Follow tmuxinator page to set it up
correctly. If you want to see my primitive configuration it is also available on
my github in <a href="https://github.com/pietrushnic/workspace/blob/master/dotfiles/tmux.conf">werkspace project</a>.</p>

<h3>Window logging</h3>

<p>Last hint I found on this
<a href="http://0xfeedface.org/blog/lattera/2012-03-19/using-tmux-screencasting-tool">blog</a>.
How to log your work in console for example to write a blog post :) ? There is a
universal method for piping all console output to our program of choice. For
example run command like this (command mode available under <code>C-b :</code>):
<code>
pipe-pane -o 'cat &gt;&gt; ~/tmuxcast.#h.#T'
</code>
This will give you file with logged session output (all curses windows, editor
windows and so on). Curses output can be unreadable because of control escape
sequences. Use <code>cat</code> it will interpret escape sequences in terminal.</p>

<p>As always I hope hints were useful. Please share this content if think its
valuable. Comment if you think id needs improvements. Thank you for reading.</p>

<p>P.S. I should probably create a footer with last paragraph :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Music for programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/music-for-programming/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T03:27:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/music-for-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Of course this is strongly associated with personal taste but I will write my
experience.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="www.pandora.com">www.pandora.com</a> &ndash; really great radio station, choose your
genre or artist and it will lead you through all variety of this type.
unfortunately if you are fan of Iron Maiden, Blind Guardian, prog rock or
irish folk you will be bored after 2 hours or less. Sadly not available in
Poland <i class='emoji disappointed'></i> &ndash; maybe some proxy will work but I wasn&rsquo;t able to find one.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kohina.com/">kohina/demo scene</a> &ndash; very good radio for long night
coding sessions. I&rsquo;m not big fan of demo scene but I appreciate what guys do
and did. And somtimes you will hit Super Mario or Contra theme.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.progarchives.com/subgenre.asp?style=32">post rock/math rock</a> &ndash; if you like any variety of prog rock you probably
know <a href="http://www.progarchives.com/">ProgArchives</a>. It is really hard to find
good prog rock radio where classics are well mixed with newcomers. I really
like to listen guys like <a href="http://www.progarchives.com/subgenre.asp?style=32">God Is An Astronaut</a>,
<a href="http://www.explosionsinthesky.com/">Explosions In The Sky</a>, <a href="http://twdy.tumblr.com/">This Will Destroy You</a>,
<a href="http://www.65daysofstatic.com/">65daysofstatic</a>, <a href="http://www.redsparowes.com/News.aspx">Red Sparowes</a> or even
<a href="http://mogwai.sandbag.uk.com/lesrevenants/">Mogwai</a> or <a href="http://www.sigur-ros.co.uk/">Sigur Ros</a>.
Very good for programming if you drink cofee/tea <i class='emoji smile'></i></li>
<li>movie soundtracks &ndash; This one I use when really need to concentrate
especially when working daylight hours. What&rsquo;s best here most of people will
agree that <a href="http://www.enniomorricone.it/uk/news.php">Ennio Moricone</a>, <a href="http://elsew.com/">Vangelis</a> and <a href="http://www.hans-zimmer.com/">Hans Zimmer</a>
are famous one and most recognizable for my generation.</li>
<li><a href="http://nsbradio.co.uk/content/">breakbeat</a> &ndash; this one reminds me some stories about mythical cyberpunk
hackers, its usually noisy and help me isolate from environment and
concentrate on my work. I will said that if you like freaked electronics than
you can try this.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.shoutcast.com/Internet-Radio/drum%20and%20base">dnb</a> &ndash; if
breakbeat is to hard for you try this <i class='emoji smile'></i>. This music tune me in channel of
rhythmical work.</li>
<li>When googling this topic I found <a href="http://musicforprogramming.net/">this site</a>
it was worth to check. Some links are broken. Most of those playlists have too
low tempo for me.</li>
</ol>


<p>I can also suggest some Irish Folk influenced stuff if don&rsquo;t have &ldquo;The End is
near&rdquo; wallpaper on your desktop <i class='emoji smile'></i> There was a time when I was listen a lot of
psybient, but it is really hard to find good psychodelic ambient radio and this
music is for me more like movie soundtracks I cannot listen it at night.
Hope it will give some kind of direction. Let me know what you listen when coding.
Maybe I will discover new universe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short hint for all those who use vim and pathogen]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/01/15/short-hint-for-all-those-who-use-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T11:51:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/01/15/short-hint-for-all-those-who-use-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, after updating my wokspace to latest version I encounter below error during vim running:
<code>
Error detected while processing function pathogen#runtime_append_all_bundles:
line 1:
E121: Undefined variable: source_path
E116: Invalid arguments for function string(source_path).') to pathogen#incubate('.string(source_path.'/{}').')')
E116: Invalid arguments for function 4_warn
Press ENTER or type command to continue
</code>
Quick look on pathogen runtime_append_all_bundles function and I found:
<code>bash
call s:warn('Change pathogen#runtime_append_all_bundles('.string(a:1).') to pathogen#incubate('.string(a:1.'/{}').')')
</code>
So simply replacing:
<code>bash
call pathogen#runtime_append_all_bundles()
</code>
with:
<code>bash
call pathogen#incubate() in $HOME/.vimrc fix the problem.
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
