<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: productivity | pietrushnic's world]]></title>
  <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/categories/productivity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-21T07:27:22+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[pietrushnic]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pierushnic@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tmux as screen replacement and productivity accelerator]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/04/06/tmux/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-06T05:29:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/04/06/tmux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I wrote in <a href="/blog/2013/03/19/debian-switching-to-unstable">previous post</a> I
switched from GNU screen to <a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net">tmux</a>. I use it for a
few moths and have to said that I'm really impressed by simplicity, performance
and community support in this project. In this post I want to discuss my
configuration and useful additions for it like tmuxinator, session logging,
colors or status bar configuration.</p>

<h3>Basics</h3>

<p>Debian contain <code>tmux</code> package but for stable and testing release it is pretty
old version. Personally I use <code>unstable</code> version where <code>tmux</code> was delivered in
<code>1.7~svn2819-1</code> version.
<code>
sudo apt-get install tmux
</code>
To start session simply type <code>tmux</code>. Tmux uses <code>C-b</code>/ <code>Ctrl-b</code> as a prefix for
commands. If you switch from GNU screen then at the beginning you can experience
some annoying situations but after few days everything should back to normal.</p>

<p>Most used keybiddings:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>C-b c</code> - create new window</li>
<li><code>C-b ,</code> - rename current window</li>
<li><code>C-b n</code> - next window</li>
<li><code>C-b p</code> - previous window</li>
<li><code>C-b l</code> - last window</li>
<li><code>C-b d</code> - disconnect</li>
<li><code>C-b k</code> - kill current window</li>
<li><code>C-b K</code> - kill tmux server</li>
<li><code>C-b [</code> - enter copy mode</li>
<li><code>C-b ]</code> - paste last copied buffer</li>
<li><code>C-b :</code> - tmux command line</li>
<li><code>C-b w</code> - windows list</li>
<li><code>C-b ?</code> - help</li>
</ul>


<p>Full list can be found <a href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi?query=tmux&amp;sektion=1#KEY+BINDINGS">here</a>.</p>

<h3>Configuration</h3>

<p>Tmux keeps its configuration in <code>$HOME/.tmux.conf</code>. My configuration mixes
some tmux examples with code that I found in the net. This file can be found on
my github repository <a href="https://github.com/pietrushnic/workspace/blob/master/dotfiles/tmux.conf">here</a>. First section contain some general configuration:
```</p>

<h1>confirm before killing a window or the server</h1>

<p>bind-key k confirm kill-window
bind-key K confirm kill-server</p>

<h1>toggle statusbar</h1>

<p>bind-key b set-option status</p>

<h1>ctrl+left/right cycles thru windows</h1>

<p>bind-key -n C-right next
bind-key -n C-left prev</p>

<h1>scrollback buffer n lines</h1>

<p>set -g history-limit 10000</p>

<h1>listen for activity on all windows</h1>

<p>set -g bell-action any</p>

<h1>on-screen time for display-panes in ms</h1>

<p>set -g display-panes-time 2000</p>

<h1>start window indexing at one instead of zero</h1>

<p>set -g base-index 1</p>

<h1>enable wm window titles</h1>

<p>set -g set-titles on</p>

<h1>wm window title string (uses statusbar variables)</h1>

<p>set -g set-titles-string "tmux.#I.#W"</p>

<h1>statusbar</h1>

<p>set -g display-time 2000
<code>
After that I have implemented [solarized](http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized) colors (dark theme):
</code></p>

<h3>COLOUR (Solarized dark)</h3>

<h1>default statusbar colors</h1>

<p>set-option -g status-bg black #base02
set-option -g status-fg yellow #yellow
set-option -g status-attr default</p>

<h1>default window title colors</h1>

<p>set-window-option -g window-status-fg brightblue #base0
set-window-option -g window-status-bg default</p>

<h1>set-window-option -g window-status-attr dim</h1>

<h1>active window title colors</h1>

<p>set-window-option -g window-status-current-fg brightred #orange
set-window-option -g window-status-current-bg default</p>

<h1>set-window-option -g window-status-current-attr bright</h1>

<h1>use vi-like keys</h1>

<p>setw -g mode-keys vi</p>

<h1>pane border</h1>

<p>set-option -g pane-border-fg black #base02
set-option -g pane-active-border-fg brightgreen #base01</p>

<h1>message text</h1>

<p>set-option -g message-bg black #base02
set-option -g message-fg brightred #orange</p>

<h1>pane number display</h1>

<p>set-option -g display-panes-active-colour blue #blue
set-option -g display-panes-colour brightred #orange
```
To make solarized colors work on my setup was quite challenging, because there
are many things to set (vim, terminal, putty etc.). If you need any advice I can
write something about this. Right now it is beyond the scope of this post.</p>

<p>At the end of my tmux configuration I've some fancy status bar:
```</p>

<h1>clock</h1>

<p>set-window-option -g clock-mode-colour green #green</p>

<h1>center align the window list</h1>

<p>set -g status-justify centre</p>

<h1>show some useful stats but only when tmux is started</h1>

<h1>outside of Xorg, otherwise dwm statusbar shows these already</h1>

<p>set -g status-right ""
set -g status-left ""
if '[ -z "$DISPLAY" ]' 'set -g status-left "[#[fg=green] #H ][#[default]]"'
if '[ -z "$DISPLAY" ]' 'set -g status-right "[ #[fg=magenta]#(cat /proc/loadavg | cut -d \" \" -f 1,2,3)#[default] ][ #[fg=cyan,bright]%a %Y-%m-%d %H:%M #[default]]"'
if '[ -z "$DISPLAY" ]' 'set -g status-right-length 50'
```
I think that mostly this is self explanatory. This how it look in work:
<a href="/assets/images/tmux-screen.png"><img class="center" src="/assets/images/tmux-screen.png" width="300" height="400"></a></p>

<h3>tmuxinator</h3>

<p>I spend some time to realize what is the best way of managing windows and panes
in tmux. Especially I was interested in setting some windows at tmux startup.
Finally I found <a href="https://github.com/aziz/tmuxinator">tmuxinator</a> small but useful
project delivered through <code>gem</code> system. Follow tmuxinator page to set it up
correctly. If you want to see my primitive configuration it is also available on
my github in <a href="https://github.com/pietrushnic/workspace/blob/master/dotfiles/tmux.conf">werkspace project</a>.</p>

<h3>Window logging</h3>

<p>Last hint I found on this
<a href="http://0xfeedface.org/blog/lattera/2012-03-19/using-tmux-screencasting-tool">blog</a>.
How to log your work in console for example to write a blog post :) ? There is a
universal method for piping all console output to our program of choice. For
example run command like this (command mode available under <code>C-b :</code>):
<code>
pipe-pane -o 'cat &gt;&gt; ~/tmuxcast.#h.#T'
</code>
This will give you file with logged session output (all curses windows, editor
windows and so on). Curses output can be unreadable because of control escape
sequences. Use <code>cat</code> it will interpret escape sequences in terminal.</p>

<p>As always I hope hints were useful. Please share this content if think its
valuable. Comment if you think id needs improvements. Thank you for reading.</p>

<p>P.S. I should probably create a footer with last paragraph :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Music for programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/music-for-programming/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T03:27:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/music-for-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Of course this is strongly associated with personal taste but I will write my
experience.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="www.pandora.com">www.pandora.com</a> - really great radio station, choose your
genre or artist and it will lead you through all variety of this type.
unfortunately if you are fan of Iron Maiden, Blind Guardian, prog rock or
irish folk you will be bored after 2 hours or less. Sadly not available in
Poland :( - maybe some proxy will work but I wasn't able to find one.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kohina.com/">kohina/demo scene</a> - very good radio for long night
coding sessions. I'm not big fan of demo scene but I appreciate what guys do
and did. And somtimes you will hit Super Mario or Contra theme.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.progarchives.com/subgenre.asp?style=32">post rock/math rock</a> - if you like any variety of prog rock you probably
know <a href="http://www.progarchives.com/">ProgArchives</a>. It is really hard to find
good prog rock radio where classics are well mixed with newcomers. I really
like to listen guys like <a href="http://www.progarchives.com/subgenre.asp?style=32">God Is An Astronaut</a>,
<a href="http://www.explosionsinthesky.com/">Explosions In The Sky</a>, <a href="http://twdy.tumblr.com/">This Will Destroy You</a>,
<a href="http://www.65daysofstatic.com/">65daysofstatic</a>, <a href="http://www.redsparowes.com/News.aspx">Red Sparowes</a> or even
<a href="http://mogwai.sandbag.uk.com/lesrevenants/">Mogwai</a> or <a href="http://www.sigur-ros.co.uk/">Sigur Ros</a>.
Very good for programming if you drink cofee/tea :)</li>
<li>movie soundtracks - This one I use when really need to concentrate
especially when working daylight hours. What's best here most of people will
agree that <a href="http://www.enniomorricone.it/uk/news.php">Ennio Moricone</a>, <a href="http://elsew.com/">Vangelis</a> and <a href="http://www.hans-zimmer.com/">Hans Zimmer</a>
are famous one and most recognizable for my generation.</li>
<li><a href="http://nsbradio.co.uk/content/">breakbeat</a> - this one reminds me some stories about mythical cyberpunk
hackers, its usually noisy and help me isolate from environment and
concentrate on my work. I will said that if you like freaked electronics than
you can try this.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.shoutcast.com/Internet-Radio/drum%20and%20base">dnb</a> - if
breakbeat is to hard for you try this :). This music tune me in channel of
rhythmical work.</li>
<li>When googling this topic I found <a href="http://musicforprogramming.net/">this site</a>
it was worth to check. Some links are broken. Most of those playlists have too
low tempo for me.</li>
</ol>


<p>I can also suggest some Irish Folk influenced stuff if don't have "The End is
near" wallpaper on your desktop :) There was a time when I was listen a lot of
psybient, but it is really hard to find good psychodelic ambient radio and this
music is for me more like movie soundtracks I cannot listen it at night.
Hope it will give some kind of direction. Let me know what you listen when coding.
Maybe I will discover new universe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short hint for all those who use vim and pathogen]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/01/15/short-hint-for-all-those-who-use-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T11:51:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2013/01/15/short-hint-for-all-those-who-use-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, after updating my wokspace to latest version I encounter below error during vim running:
<code>
Error detected while processing function pathogen#runtime_append_all_bundles:
line 1:
E121: Undefined variable: source_path
E116: Invalid arguments for function string(source_path).') to pathogen#incubate('.string(source_path.'/{}').')')
E116: Invalid arguments for function 4_warn
Press ENTER or type command to continue
</code>
Quick look on pathogen runtime_append_all_bundles function and I found:
<code>bash
call s:warn('Change pathogen#runtime_append_all_bundles('.string(a:1).') to pathogen#incubate('.string(a:1.'/{}').')')
</code>
So simply replacing:
<code>bash
call pathogen#runtime_append_all_bundles()
</code>
with:
<code>bash
call pathogen#incubate() in $HOME/.vimrc fix the problem.
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim as a Blogger editor]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2012/04/21/vim-as-blogger-editor_21/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-21T12:55:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2012/04/21/vim-as-blogger-editor_21</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  <a href="https://github.com/ujihisa/blogger.vim">Blogger.vim</a> is a vim plugin for interfacing with Google's Blogger. Below I will use my workspace git <a href="https://github.com/pietrushnic/workspace">repository</a>. To use this plugin we need pretty new ruby >= 1.9.2 and gems nokogiri and net-https-wrapper. Let's install latest possible ruby for Debian, before that make sure you have latest updates:</p>

<p>sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get upgrade sudo apt-get dist-upgrade And ruby:</p>

<p>sudo apt-get install ruby1.9.3 Before we install gems , we need to resolve some dependencies:</p>

<p>sudo apt-get install libxml2-dev libxslt1-dev Latest nokogiri 1.5.2 have some issues, so we need to use 1.5.0 which is stable:</p>

<p>sudo gem install nokogiri --version 1.5.0 And the wrapper for https:</p>

<p>sudo gem install net-https-wrapper Finally also pandoc will be neded to display web pages in vim:</p>

<p>sudo apt-get install pandoc Right now we are able to run vim with blogger support. First we need to configure vim, add below lines to your $HOME/.vimrc file:</p>

<p>let g:blogger_blogid = 'your_blogid_here' let g:blogger_email = 'your_email_here' let g:blogger_pass = 'your_blogger_password_here' Run vim and try to list your blogger posts by typing:</p>

<p>:e blogger:list If list of you see all your posts than it seems that plugin works good. Finally check writing feature. Create file with some text and type:</p>

<p>:w blogger:create Few things doesn't work as it should. Meybe I will find enough time to fix it. This article was created by using blogger.vim script.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Splitting my personal repository]]></title>
    <link href="http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2012/03/14/splitting-my-personal-repository/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T23:26:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://pietrushnic.github.io/blog/2012/03/14/splitting-my-personal-repository</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After writing a few posts in which my workspace scripts could be useful, I
realized that I should split blog works from the scripts that can be useful to
others. From now materials related to the blog I will track in a separate
repository and I'll add them as submodule into my environment. This implies that
if we intend to deliver something to a broader audience this should include only
those things which the recipient is expected and which we say that we provide.
Any additional items should be removed. We get a lot of unwanted stuff today, at
every opportunity. From an economic point of view, it is known that very often
margin value law is used here i.e. by hypermarkets, I will touch on this subject
on another occasion, related to economics.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
